(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T04:32:48.404589",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
In a repeating world, how many times
僅かな涙は黒い心溶かすの？
must I reach out my hand?
芽生え出した想いが胸に響いたなら
If the feelings that began to bud resonate in my chest,
君の隣でずっと変わらず守るだろう
I will stay by your side and protect you forever.
落ちた希望を拾って明日へ繋いでゆけば
If I pick up fallen hope and connect it to tomorrow,
絡まった歪んだ願いだってほぐれる
even tangled, distorted wishes will untangle.
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I held up the light and erased my hesitation.
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you was the future.
泣いている夜抱いたまま嘆きを叫んで
Crying out my grief while holding the weeping night,
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想がそっと癒やしてゆく
distant ideals gently heal the steps I've taken.
確かな絆を強く握り進もうどこまでも
Gripping our certain bond tightly, I'll advance anywhere.
穢れきった奇跡を背に
With stained miracles upon my back,
創られた想い触れれば何よりも
If I touch these artificial feelings, more than anything
温かくて現実が霞み始める
they are warm, and reality begins to blur.
狂い出した世界に問いかけ続けても
Even if I keep questioning a world gone mad,
答えなんて出ないってもう君は知っていたの
you already knew that no answer would come.
泣いて滲んだ願いは決して揺らぎはしなくて
My tear-stained wish will never waver,
ただそっと終わりなく与える
simply and endlessly granting pain.
悲しみを知って喜びを知った
I came to know sorrow, I came to know joy.
弱さは君を変えて立ち止まった時剥ぎ取る全てを壊した
Weakness changed you, destroying everything stripped away when you stopped.
届くはずのない言葉を託して
Entrusting words that were never meant to reach,
見えた瞳は何を感じて遠ざかるの
what do those eyes feel as they grow distant?
今ここにいる意味 教えてくれたなら
If you had taught me the meaning of being here now,
強く居られる 変わらずいつも
I could stay strong, forever unchanged.
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
In a repeating world, how many times must I reach out?
僅かな涙は黒い心溶かすの？
Will these fleeting tears dissolve my black heart?
芽生え出した想いが胸に響いたなら 君の隣でずっと変わらず守ろうだろう
If budding feelings resonate in my chest, I will protect them by your side forever.
躓いた希望を拾って 明日に繋いでゆけば
If we pick up fallen hopes and connect them to tomorrow,
絡まった歪な願いだってほぐれる
even entangled, distorted wishes will unravel.
光をかざして 躊躇いを消した あがけたのは未来で
Raising the light, dispelling hesitation, what I struggled for was the future.
泣いてる夜抱いたまま 嘆き叫んで
Embracing the weeping night, shouting out grief,
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が そっと癒やしてゆく
the steps I took are gently healed by distant ideals.
確かな絆を強く握り進め どこまでも
Let's firmly grasp the certain bond and move forward anywhere.
狂い出した世界に問いかけ続けても
Even if I keep questioning the world that went mad,
答えなんて出ないって もう君は知っていたの？
did you already know there would be no answers?
泣いて泣き滲んだ願いは 決して揺らぎはしないで
Tear-stained wishes will never waver,
ただそっと痛みを余りなく与える
simply and quietly bestowing endless pain.
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
"Hello there, I am your doppelgänger."
何の冗談かと目を擦ってみる
Rubbing my eyes at such a joke,
影がふたつ伸びて
two shadows stretch out,
そしてまた幕は上がる
and the curtain rises once again.
「もう一人の自分がいたら」
"If only there was another me,"
とあなたは言いました
you said back then.
「そんな紳士な願いが
"Such a gentlemanly wish
僕を呼んだのさ」
is what called me here."
そりゃ願ったとて カナンシンク すべてのエージェント
Even if you wished for it, agent of can't-think,
過程はないから 結果をください
with no process, give me the result.
無意味で無意味な代償
A meaningless, meaningless price to pay.
ねえ こんなことより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろう
Hey, there's something more important than this, right?
「ええ やりますやります 何でもやります
"Yes, I'll do anything, I'll do it all,
僕は君の分身です」
I am your doppelgänger."
含み笑いをしてメシアは言う
The messiah says with a subtle smile.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰
Dear doppelgänger, who, who are you?
呻呼混雑と交差して 僕は誰？
Crossing with groans and chaos, who am I?
ねえ 有りもしない 0 と 1
Hey, non-existent zeros and ones,
証明の根拠なんて 何処にも
there's no basis for proof anywhere.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君
Dear doppelgänger, who, who are you?
蠢かされた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice this wriggling existence.
鳴り止まない 眠り止まない 奇跡の輪廻が
An endless, sleepless reincarnation of miracles
狂った正解を塗り上げて ランパパ
paints over the maddened correct answer, lampapa.
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Monday, when something feels off,
一つ二つと崩れゆく秩序が 僕を弑する
one by one, crumbling order slays me.
お前はいったい誰だ と
Asking, "Just who are you?"
ちょっと待って 知らないけど知りもしない言葉
Wait a minute, words I don't know and don't care to know,
どや顔のままで影は溶けてゆく
with a smug face, the shadow melts away.
僕は一体何なんだろう
Just what on earth am I?
ねえ どうか存在を返して
Hey, please give back my existence.
「生生しいがこっちはこっちはで
"Though gruesome, over here on this side,
随分居心地が良くてさ」
it's quite comfortable."
「もうあなたの居場所は此処にはない事
"You know very well that your place
分かってるんでしょう？」
is no longer here, right?"
「ねえ 奪われたなら 奪えばいいだろ
"Hey, if it was stolen, just steal it back,
今度は お前の番だからさ」
because this time it's your turn."
含み笑いをしてインベーダーは謀る
The invader plots with a subtle smile.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰
Dear doppelgänger, who, who are you?
呻呼混雑と交差して 僕は誰？
Crossing with groans and chaos, who am I?
もう止まらない モデラない
No longer stopping, not moderating,
どうもこんにちは 君の
hello there, to your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それはそれは僕
Dear doppelgänger, that, that is me.
それは ずっと続く人間の業の連鎖
It's the unending chain of human karma.
委ね合って 許し合って 満たされて往く
Entrusting, forgiving, and becoming fulfilled.
欠けたピース 無価値のペイン 矜持また愛も
Missing pieces, worthless pain, pride and love too,
託し合って 生まれ換わる
entrusting to each other, we are reborn.
「僕の方がちゃんと君を生かしてやるから」
"I'll make sure to keep you properly alive,"
「君も次の誰かちゃんと救わなくちゃね」
"and you have to properly save the next person too."
「もうわかってるんだろ
"You already understand,
何をすればいいかさ」
what you need to do, right?"
どうか大家に奇跡をくれよ
Please, grant a miracle to the great house.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰
Dear doppelgänger, who, who are you?
呻呼混雑と交差して 僕は誰？
Crossing with groans and chaos, who am I?
もっともっとないもっとない
Wanting more and more, having nothing more,
どうもこんにちは 君の
hello there, to your...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それはそれは僕
Dear doppelgänger, that, that is me.
蠢かされた存在に 世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice this wriggling existence.
僕が君の分身です
I am your alter ego.
考える このままいつまで 隠しておけるから
I wonder how long I can keep hiding it like this.
帰りたくなったとき さよならは言えるから
When you want to go home, I can say goodbye.
見落とした あの日のサインが 少しずつ溶けても
Even if the signs I missed that day melt away bit by bit,
きっと大丈夫だよ
I'm sure it'll be fine.
こうやって僕らは出会えるから
Because this is how we meet.
目を閉じる 小さな祈りには まだ残せるから
In a small prayer with my eyes closed, I can still leave something behind.
光が戻ったとき
When the light returns,
ただいまは言えるから
I can say "I'm home".
行かなくちゃ 世界で一番 綺麗なものなら
I must go, if it's the most beautiful thing in the world,
今まで奪われてた分は 取り戻すまでさ
I'll take back everything that was stolen from me until now!
もっと グラグラグラグラ狂わせてよ
More! Drive me crazy, swaying back and forth,
揺ら揺ら揺ら揺ら見つめてよ
gaze at me, swaying gently,
キラキラキラキラ輝いてよ
shine brightly, sparkling!
そっと傷ついた夜を呼び出してみる
Softly, I try calling out the wounded night,
ささやかな魔法をひとつかける
casting a single, simple magic spell.
それだけでも僕らはすべてのさ
Even with just that, we can conquer everything—
魔法が溶ける その日まで 繋いでいてよ 手を 手を 手を
until the magic fades, hold my hand, my hand, my hand!
一つだって残さない すべてを取り戻すだけさ
Not a single thing left behind, we'll take back everything!
魔法が溶ける その日まで 繋いでいてよ 手を 手を 手を
Until the magic fades, hold my hand, my hand, my hand!
今まで奪われてた分は 取り戻すまでさ
Until now, all that was stolen from us, we'll take it back!
そっと傷ついた夜を呼び出してみる
Softly, I try calling out the wounded night,
ささやかな魔法をひとつかける
casting a single, simple magic spell.
もっとグラグラグラグラ狂わせてよ
More! Drive me crazy, swaying back and forth,
揺ら揺ら揺ら揺ら見つめてよ
gaze at me, swaying gently,
キラキラキラキラ輝いてよ
shine brightly, sparkling!
離さないでよ 物語を
Don't let go of the story,
魔法が溶ける その日まで
until the magic fades.
繋いでいてよ 手を 手を 手を
Hold my hand, my hand, my hand!
一つだって残さない すべてを取り戻すだけさ
Not a single thing left behind, we'll take back everything!
魔法が溶ける その日まで 繋いでいてよ 手を 手を 手を
Until the magic fades, hold my hand, my hand, my hand!
皆さん、こんにちは！ときのそらです！
Hello everyone! I'm Tokino Sora!
楽曲から3曲歌わせていただきました！
I've just performed three songs right from the start!
みんな見えてる？聞こえてる？
Can everyone see me? Can you hear me?
コメントたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all the comments!
はろーえぶりわん！
Hello everyone!
今日見に来てくれてとっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy you came to see me today!
今のテオ、画面の映像どうでしたか？
What did you think of the video on screen during "Teo" just now?
すごい綺麗な演出もあったんですけど、見てくれたかなみんな？
There were some amazing, beautiful visual effects too. Did you all see them?
あとね、ステージも見て！ すごい！めちゃくちゃ豪華！
And look at the stage too! It's amazing! So gorgeous!
こんな素敵なステージを作ってくださって本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for creating such a wonderful stage!
さあ、そんな今日なんですが、
Now then, as for today's stream,
ぜひぜひこちらときのそら生誕祭ライブで
please, everyone, at this Tokino Sora Birthday Live,
楽しんでいただけたら、とっても嬉しいなって思います。
I'd be so happy if you enjoy it.
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ハローハロー！
Happy birthday to me! Hello, hello!
なんかすごい最初からね、3曲連続全力疾走みたいな感じで歌わせていただいたが、
It feels like right from the start, we sang three songs in a row like an earnest dash.
まあ今日はですね、いっぱい曲を歌って、まあ私のワンマンライブみたいなイメージで
Well, today, we're going to sing lots of songs, giving the image of my one-man live,
ちょっとね、色々と歌っていこうかなと思っております。たくさん歌っていくのでぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいなと思いますし、
and I'm thinking of singing all sorts of songs. I'll be singing a lot, so I'd be really happy if you can enjoy it all the way to the end.
まあね、この後には
Well, you know, afterwards,
最後のほうにはちょっと、ちょっと何か見せたいものもあったりするからね、見てくださいね。
towards the end, there's something a little special I want to show you, so please look forward to it.
よろしくお願いします。返事します。今日初めて私を知ったっていう人も
Please check it out! Even if you're someone who is just getting to know me today,
ぜひぜひ見てもらえると嬉しいよ！
I'd be so happy if you watch it too!
さあ、次の曲はね
Now, for the next song,
みんなにまったりと聞いてほしいなと思っているので、ちょっと衣装も変えっかななんて思ってます。
I want everyone to listen to leisurely, so I'm thinking of changing my outfit a bit.
とりあえず真ん中に移動しようかな！
For now, let's move to the center!
みんな！ありがとう！ありがとう！見えてるよ！ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you! Thank you! I can see you! Thank you!
みんな見て！見えてる？見えてる？見えてる？ありがとう！大好きだよ！コメントもありがとう！
Everyone, look! Can you see? Can you see? Thank you! I love you! Thank you for the comments too!
みんなありがとう！大好きだよ！これからもしっとりした歌をうたうからいっぱい聴いてもらえると嬉しいです！ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you! I love you! I'll be singing more touching songs from now on, so I'd be happy if you listen to lots of them! Thank you!
それでは聞いてください、プロローグ。
Now then, please listen: Prologue.
目にかかる髪の毛と 掻き分けた指
Hair falling over my eyes, fingers brushed aside
壊れそうでおどこか 寂しげな背中
A back that looked broken and somewhat lonely
頼りない太陽を 滲ませながら
As the unreliable sun blurred
微笑んだ その横顔 見つめていた
I gazed at your smiling profile
いつの間にかその全て 視界に入ってくるの
Before I knew it, all of that came into view
心が波打つ 痛み に どうして 気づいてしまったの
How did I become aware of the pain that made my heart ripple?
あなたを 探してる
I'm looking for you
隠した瞳の奥で
deep inside my hidden eyes
誰にも見えないように 行き場もなくて彷徨いながら
so no one can see, wandering with nowhere to go
あなたと見る世界は いつでも綺麗だった
The world I see with you was always beautiful
空にはひとつだけ 淡く光る小さな星が残っている
There's only one small, faintly shining star left in the sky
雪原もなくて彷徨いながら あなたを
wandering with nowhere to go, seeking and pushing away
見る世界は いつでも綺麗だった
The world I see was always beautiful
ひとつだけ 青く光る 小さな星が 残っている
A small star remains, shining pale and bright
小さな星が 残っている
A small star remains shining bright
どんなす 夢ないこころ
A heart devoid of dreams...
見つめられることに嘘がつけない
can't lie to what it gazes at.
力なく点滅する あの街灯を
I looked up at that flickering streetlight,
見上げてた その横顔は優しかった
and your profile looked so gentle.
破れそうに膨らんで 僕に触れた果実は
The fruit that swelled as if to burst and touched me...
誰かの爪を待っているね それは私だった
is waiting for someone's nail... That was me.
あなたが溢れていく 押さえた
Overflowing with you, I tried to hold back
胸の数だけ 隠せない始まりを
the beginning I couldn't hide, matching my heartbeat.
過ぎたら次へ 手のひらに伝えていくよ
Passing by, moving on to the next, I'll convey it in my palm.
数は冷たいのに ソナタ心は赤いまま
Even though the numbers are cold, my sonata heart remains red.
あなたに触れたいと思ってしまったどうして
Why did I think I wanted to touch you?
二人であったの
that we met, just the two of us?
いたくて苦しくて それなら
If it hurts and aches so much,
見えないように どこかへ飛んでゆけ
fly away somewhere so it can't be seen.
そのものに あなたを探している なんと
Searching for you in that very thing... somehow...
名前を呼んで それには一つだけ
Calling your name, there's only one thing to that.
淡く光る 小さな星を浮かべて
Floating a faintly glowing, tiny star,
Beyond
作詞・作曲：草野華余子
[Song: Beyond
Lyrics & Music: Kayoko Kusano]
夕映えに揺蕩う 少し伸びた前髪
Flickering in the twilight, my slightly grown bangs
とけぼうし 巡る日々
and the fleeting days going by.
楽しかった分だけ 今日が終わってしまうことが どうしても寂しくなるけど
Even though I inevitably feel lonely that today ends just as much as it was fun,
忘れないで 同じ空を見上げていること どんな君だって愛しく思うから
don't forget that we're looking up at the same sky, because I cherish you no matter who you are.
大丈夫、大丈夫だって歌うから
I'll sing that it's going to be alright, it'll be alright.
変わっていく中で 変わらない気持ちで ずっと大丈夫だって歌うから
Amidst all changes, with unchanging feelings, I'll keep singing that it'll be alright.
時間も距離も超えて 心は側にあるから
Transcending time and distance, my heart is right by your side.
通り雨に濡れて 凍えた爪先じゃ上手く歩けずに
Soaked in a passing shower, with frozen toes unable to walk well,
窓の日に 悲しかった分だけ 明日が少しでも
just as much as I felt sad by the window, so tomorrow can shine even a little bit...
夕映えに揺蕩う 少し伸びた前髪 とけぼうし 巡る日々
Swaying in the evening glow, slightly grown-out bangs, passing days...
楽しかった分だけ 今日が終わってしまうことが
Just because we had fun, the fact that today is ending
どうしても寂しくなるけど
somehow makes me feel lonely, but
忘れないで 同じ空を見上げていること
don't forget that we're looking up at the same sky.
どんな君だって愛しく思うから
Because no matter what kind of you it is, I hold it dear.
大丈夫 大丈夫だって歌うから
It's okay, I'll sing that it's okay, so
変わっていく中で 変わらない気持ちで
amidst the changing times, with unchanging feelings,
ずっと大丈夫だって歌うから 時間も距離も越えて 心は側にあるから
I'll always sing that it's okay, because across time and distance, my heart is by your side.
通り雨に濡れて 凍えた爪先じゃ 上手に歩けずに 焦る日々
Getting caught in a passing shower, with frozen toes unable to walk well, days of panic...
悲しかった分だけ 明日が一番輝くように いつだって願っているから
Wishing always that tomorrow will shine brightest, proportional to the sadness we felt.
一緒にかけがえのない時を重ねていこうよ どこまでも
Let's stack up irreplaceable moments together, no matter how far.
頑張れない日も 涙が出ない夜も
Even on days we can't try hard, even on nights tears won't fall,
大丈夫 大丈夫だって歌うから
It's okay, I'll sing that it's okay, so
新しい一歩を
a new step forward...
君が踏み出す日も ちゃんと大丈夫だって歌うから
On the day you step out too, I'll sing properly that it's okay, so
そうちっぽくな僕ら 心揺れながらも
Yes, even with our small selves, with our wavering hearts,
大切を重ねて未来を描く
we stack up precious things and paint the future.
どんな僕だって愛してくれたこと
The fact that you loved every bit of me,
いつだって いつだって忘れないから
I will never, ever forget it, so
変わっていく中で 変わらない気持ちで
amidst the changing times, with unchanging feelings,
僕の精一杯で返すから どんな君だって愛しく思うから
I'll return it with my absolute best, because no matter what kind of you it is, I hold it dear.
大丈夫 大丈夫だって歌うから
It's okay, I'll sing that it's okay, so
たどり着いた今日の日に 君という光に出会えた
On today's day we arrived at, I was able to meet a light called you.
僕から 大丈夫 大丈夫だって歌うから
From me, I'll sing that it's okay, so
時間も距離も越えて 心は側にあるから
because across time and distance, my heart is by your side,
越えて 心は側にあるから
crossing over, my heart is by your side.
はい！ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much!
ここではプロローグ、ビヨンドと、2曲続けて歌わせていただきました。
Here, we sang two songs in a row: "Prologue" and "Beyond."
いやあ、バラードをね、挑戦したいなと思って、今回はねいろんな挑戦をいろいろやっていこうというわけで、
Man, I wanted to challenge myself with ballads, so this time I wanted to try out all sorts of challenges,
最初の3曲は、なんていうんだろう、なんか自分の中で難しいと思って行った
and for the first three songs, how should I put it, songs that I thought were difficult for myself,
早くて高くてみたいな、でもかっこよくてみたいな、
fast and high and stuff, but also cool and stuff,
そういう曲。あ、パチパチみんなさんありがとうございます。
songs like that. Ah, everyone, thank you for the applause.
お、なんか選んでみまして、
Oh, I tried choosing them,
次のゾーンは、ええ、まあ、なんて言うんでしょうね、バラード、普段あんまり挑戦することのないバラードを歌ってみました。
and for the next zone, um, well, how should I say it, ballads—ballads that I don't usually challenge myself with, I tried singing them.
みんな盛り上がってね、盛り上がってっていう曲じゃないけど盛り上がってて。
Everyone got hyped—well, it's not really a "get hyped" song, but you got hyped!
そして、なんとね、初めて、ここの真ん中のステージを使ったんです！みんなこっちのステージも見てよー！
And, what's more, for the first time, we used the center stage here! Everyone, look at this stage too!
かわいい！あ、なんか上に、もうなんかありますね。これは、これじゃなんだろうね、ということで、あ、ありがとうございます。感動ありがとう。いや、こちらこそありがとうございます。
So cute! Ah, there's something up there already. What could this be? So, ah, thank you. Thank you for the emotion. No, thank you instead.
いやあ、みんなたくさんコメントして、たくさんつぶやいてね！いっぱいつぶやいてくれると、いっぱいチャットしてくれると、私とっても嬉しい！
Man, everyone, post lots of comments and tweet a lot! If you tweet a lot and chat a lot, I'm super happy!
そして、え、こんな豪華になったステージなんですけど、よく見るといろんなところにね、工夫がありまして、
And, um, this stage has become so luxurious, but if you look closely, there are ingenious touches everywhere,
例えばね、こことか、ここにあるね、あ、そうそうそう、これ、あ、カメラマンさんありがとうございます。こちら、アンキモと星がね、いるとかね、そう、なんかアンキモはね、どこでも見守ってくれていいるみたいな感じなんですよね。
for example, here and here, ah, that's right, this—ah, cameraman-san, thank you. Here, Ankimono and stars are here, and stuff. You know, Ankimono watches over me everywhere, it feels like that.
後ろの方もとってもかわいいですね。
The back part is also super cute.
お水飲みました。
I drank some water.
そして、そして、この全体を見ると、ここにね、こういうのがあったりとか、水色とピンクで、もうね、全体的にピンクと水色を、すごい便利に使ったステージに
And, and, if you look at the whole thing, there are things like this here, and with light blue and pink, overall, a stage making great and convenient use of pink and light blue...
なっています
are ready.
こんな素敵なステージでね、歌えるなんて本当に幸せですし、
I'm truly happy to be able to sing on such a wonderful stage,
こんなたくさんのコメントで、みんなといっしょに盛り上がっていけるのも楽しいです。本当にありがとうございます。
and it's so much fun getting hyped together with all your comments. Thank you so much!
そう、次はどんなゾーンになっているのかな？
Now, what kind of zone is coming up next?
衣装をチェンジしちゃおうかな？
Shall I change my outfit?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
見えてるー？
Can you see me?
1階のみんなー！
Everyone on the first floor!
前のみんなー！
Everyone in the front!
そしてコメントもー！わあ！うれしい！
And everyone in the chat! Wow, I'm so happy!
みんなー！こんなに素敵なステージでみんなといっしょに
Everyone! Together on such a wonderful stage,
お誕生日配信ができて幸せだー！
celebrating my birthday live makes me so happy!
幸せだー！ありがとー！
So happy! Thank you!
いつも見てくれてありがとね！
Thank you for always watching!
みんなが曲とか振りを覚えてこうやって見に来てくれてるの本当に嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy you learned the songs and choreography to come see me!
ありがとー！うれしい！うれしい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
あんきもー！
Ankimo!
あんきもー！あんきもー！あんきもー！
Ankimo! Ankimo! Ankimo!
なんで？
Why?
というわけで、なんとここからはあんきもと一緒にステージをや りたいだと思ってて、
So, starting from here, I wanted us to do the stage together with Ankimo,
踊れる？あんきも練習してきた？練習してきた？本当？本当？
can you dance? Did you practice, Ankimo? Did you practice? Really?
というわけで、ここからはあんきもと一緒にいじめてないよ！
So from here, together with Ankimo—I'm not bullying him!
これは私の愛情表現、あ、あんきもは私の愛情表現だから！
This is my way of showing affection, ah, Ankimo is my love!
だとなにものは持ってくるね？
What are you bringing out?
じゃあ、ここからは一緒に踊っていこうか！
Well then, let's dance together from here!
それじゃあ行くよ！
Here we go!
それでは聞いてください、夢空ファンファーレ！
Please listen to "Yumezora Fanfare"!
約束した今日の日を 一生忘れないそんな気がした
I felt like I'd never forget today's promised day.
ユメゾラの下で
Right beneath the dream sky,
あの空の向こう側 行ってみたいなって
"I'd love to go beyond that sky,"
覗き込んだ望遠鏡 宝探しみたいだ
peering through a telescope like treasure hunting.
「好き」が夢を叶えるって 誰かが言ってた
Someone once said that "love" makes dreams come true.
思いっきり泣いたり笑ったり
Crying and laughing to our heart's content,
全速前進でしょ！？
full speed ahead, right?!
ああ夜明けが星座を追い越した時
Ah, when dawn overtakes the constellations,
流れる星が光った
a shooting star shines bright.
一つだけ願うのなら 夢が叶う瞬間
If I could wish for just one thing, it's the moment dreams come true.
そばにいてくれますか？
Will you stay by my side?
見に行こう
Let's go see it!
ハッピーエンドのファンファーレ
The happy ending fanfare,
キラキラの未来へ
toward a sparkly future.
星に負けない光と 鳴り響く希望響かせ
Resonating hope and a light brighter than the stars,
涙と涙が重なって 空が明けるように
like tears overlapping to bring the dawn sky.
夢と夢がギュッと重なる瞬間を 奇跡と呼ぶんだ
The moment dreams tightly overlap is what we call a miracle.
空が晴れるように
Like the sky clearing up,
夢と夢がギュッと重なる瞬間を 奇跡と呼ぶんだ
the moment dreams tightly overlap is what we call a miracle.
奇跡と呼ぶんだ
Calling it a miracle!
辿り着いては いつだって
Whenever we finally arrive,
君のその笑顔
there's always your smile.
遠回りしたけど 出会えたんだ
We took the long way around, but we met.
一緒 一緒でしょ？
We'll be together, right?
キラめく希望のメロディー描いて
Drawing a shimmering melody of hope,
夢に会いに行こう
let's go meet our dreams!
見つけてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for finding me.
大切なキミへ いつの日でも
To you, my precious one,
一番に届けよう
I want to reach you first, always.
見てて 私 ここで 歌い続けること
Watch me as I keep singing right here,
約束するから
because I promise you.
約束どおり また歌ったよ
Just as promised, I sang again!
キミの声を聞かせてよ
Let me hear your voice,
道を照らす月のように （ずっとずっとずっと）
like the moon illuminating the path (always, always, always).
ハッピーエンドのファンファーレ
A happy ending fanfare—
一緒に叶えよう
let's make it come true together!
見たことのない世界へ ステップ踏んで飛び出そう
Let's step out into a world we've never seen!
笑顔と笑顔が重なって 虹がかかるように
As smiles overlap to form a rainbow,
夢と夢がギュッと重なる瞬間を
the moment when dreams tightly intertwine,
奇跡と呼ぶんだ
we call a miracle.
行こうよ ユメゾラの向こうへ
Let's go beyond the dream sky!
さあ、こちらもホップステップで歌った曲です！
Now, this is also a song I sang with hop-steps!
愛言葉Ⅳ みんなも盛り上がっていってね！
Aikotoba IV! Everyone, get hyped up!
想像なんてしてなかった 現状
A reality I never could have imagined,
キミもそう思った 最高
you thought so too, it's the best.
で止まらないように 更新したい
To make sure it doesn't stop, I want to update it.
叶えたい夢まで 誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To dreams we want to fulfill, to places no one has been,
たどり着くまでは 僕ら止まれない
until we arrive, we cannot stop.
多分嫉妬しちゃうけど どうかよろしくね
I'll probably get jealous, but please treat me well.
ねえねえ たまにねえねえ 僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Hey, hey, sometimes, hey, hey, things I can't create by myself,
僕とかキミとかあたしとか 恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
me, you, I, romance, love, putting it all together—
君を置いてどっかに 行っちゃうとかありえないよ
leaving you behind to go somewhere else is impossible.
キミがくれた音に 弾けた火花に 初めてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since the first time, I've fallen in love with the sound you gave me, the sparkling sparks.
キミのいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で それがいいじゃん
From now on, too, just the two of us, isn't that nice?
一人になるほど逃げた日もあったよ
There were days I ran away until I was all alone.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to a mess like me.
キミのいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で それがいいじゃん
From now on, too, just the two of us, isn't that nice?
膨らんでくストーリー 感ショウ やけにへこんじゃって
A swelling story, sentimental, feeling so down,
求めすぎはヤヨ 終わらない愛の連鎖はどうでしょう
seeking too much is no good, how about an endless chain of love?
ねえねえ おいでおいで 僕がキミにできること まだまだあるけど 驚かせたいから 内緒なんだ
Hey, hey, come here, come here, there's still so much I can do for you, but I want to surprise you so it's a secret.
キミの愛が いつも勝っちゃうこと 許せないよ キミ以外はヤダ 我慢はタダ
I can't forgive your love always winning. I hate anyone other than you, holding back is free.
変わらないトキメキを 絶叫しちゃうのはバカ
Screaming out about an unchanging thrill is foolish.
想像なんてしてなかった現状
Imagining was just the status quo,
君もそう思った
and you thought so too.
最高で止まらないように 更新したい
To keep it going at its best, I wanted to update it.
叶えたい夢まで 誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place nobody's ever been before,
たどり着くまでは 僕ら止まれない
until we reach it, we won't stop.
僕だけじゃ作れないモノ
Things we can't make alone,
僕とか君とかあすとか 恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
me and you, this and that, love and romance all put together,
君を置いてどっかに 行っちゃうとか
leaving you behind to go somewhere else?
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
The sparks bursting from the sound you gave me,
初めてからずっと 恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been falling in love ever since we first met.
君のいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you,
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
from now on too, it's better if there's two of us.
一途になるほど 逃げたくなもなったよ
I got so devoted I didn't even want to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thanks for calling out my messy self.
君のいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you,
これから先も二人で
from now on too, the two of us...
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Fantasy, swelling story,
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentimental, getting totally depressed,
代償 求め過ぎはやーよ
Substitution, asking for way too much,
終わらない愛の盟連結
an endless alliance of love.
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
I want to surprise you because I'm shy,
君の愛がいつも 勝ていちゃうこと
your love always ends up winning,
許さないよ 君以外はヤダ
I won't allow it, anyone other than you is a no.
我儘はタダ
My selfishness is a given.
変わらないトキメキを 絶叫しちゃうのはバカ
Screaming out that you never change is so foolish.
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
The sparks bursting from the sound you gave me,
初めてからずっと 恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been falling in love ever since we first met.
君のいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you,
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
from now on too, it's better if there's two of us.
一途になるほど 逃げたくなもなったよ
I got so devoted I didn't even want to run away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thanks for calling out my messy self.
はい というわけで 夢空ハーフアーで
And that was "Aikotoba IV"!
と合言葉フォーでした！
That was "Aikotoba IV"!
いぇーい！ 初めてで歌ったね！
Yay! We sang it for the first time!
このブライト衣装で やあ、どうでしたか？
How was it in this bright outfit?
いや、ここでは ホースフェスの再現がしたいなと思って
Well, here, I wanted to recreate Holofes,
ちょっとね、歌いました。
so I went ahead and sang it.
ホースフェス みんな思い出せたかな？
Holofes, everyone, did you remember it?
いぇーい！ そしてあんきも ありがとう！
Yay! And Ankimo, thank you!
あんきもも一生懸命踊ってくれました！ いぇーい！
Ankimo danced so hard for us too. Yay!
ぱちぱちありがとうございます！
A big thank you,ぱちぱち!
やっぱね、このブライト衣装で やっぱりホースフェスの曲がどうしても歌いたかったっていう気持ちがありまして
Man, in this bright outfit, I really, really wanted to sing a Holofes song,
それでここにれました。
and that's why I included it here.
息が... 息が切れてる。あんきももあってて
My breath... my breath is running out. Ankimo is here too,
ちょっと待って。
Look at him go.
お尻ホリホリしてろ。
He's doing the hori-hori.
ただいまー。
Right now...
なんか なんか
Wait, was he...
なんかアピールしてた？ アピールしてた？私、誕生日なんだけどアピールしてた？
Was he trying to appeal? Saying it's his birthday?
あんきもの誕生日だぞって思ってた？
Did he think it was Ankimo's birthday?
そんなことない？
No way, right?
まあ、あんきももね 私の大事な子だから
Well, Ankimo is also someone very important to me.
そして、この後なんです が
And then, after this, actually...
さらに、実はサプライズがー！
a surprise is coming!
あーー！
Ahhh!
ねなーいて言ったらどうなると思うみんな？あ、びっくりすっかな。
If I don't sleep, what do you think will happen? Everyone will be surprised, right?
あります！
There is!
ええ、昨日もね、あの予想配信とかもしたんですけど
Yesterday, you know, I also did a countdown stream,
サムネのね、このロゴにもちょっとね、ヒントがあるということでね
and the thumbnail logo gave a bit of a hint, right?
みんな、どんなのが来るかなっていうの楽しみにしててね！
Everyone's having fun wondering what kind of guests will come!
がく、がくじゃないよみんな！
Well, it's not a guest, everyone!
それでは、次の曲 なんだと思いますかー？
Now, what do you think the next song is?
何かなー？何かなー？みんなわかるかなー？
What could it be? What could it be? Does everyone know?
逆にびっくり、ね。逆にびっくりだよね。
Or rather, you'd be surprised, right? You'd be surprised!
じゃあ、次の曲は アップテンポな曲にしよっかな！
So, let's make the next song an up-tempo one!
一緒に盛り上がっていこー！
Let's get hyped up together!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
Hey DJ かませ yeah yeah yeah 気分上々↑↑の
Hey DJ, play it, yeah, yeah, yeah, feeling great!
針 落とせ 音 鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ!
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-hop people, play that miracle number!
気分上々↑↑
Feeling great!
あんきもラップ よろしく！
Ankimo Rap, let's go!
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ play it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number!
Yo! こんな時代に分かち合う music
Yo! Sharing music in these times,
探したくて回す地球儀
spinning the globe in search of it.
ぐらつく不安定生活 それだからバランス重視
Faltering lives, so balance is key.
良いことばかりじゃないから「頑張れる！」
It's not all good, so "we can keep trying!"
最悪な日にキック
Give that worst day a kick,
再起動のボタン クリック！
click the restart button!
DJ かけて！！ 今 trip
DJ, play it!! Now trip,
シャレてるビートに乗って 感じる身体揺そうよ
feel the stylish beat and rock your body!
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ play it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
hip hop,
R&B,
pops,
techno, house, rock...
hip-pop!!
オリジナル探す キーポイント それぞれの色重ね合わせ レインボー
Searching for originality, overlapping colors to make a rainbow.
君に聞かせたいが為 苦しむあがきの果て 十字固め
Wanting you to hear it after all the struggle... cross hold!
今を楽しみたいんだね
I wanna have fun now,
Let's hip-pop!! here we, here we go!!
はしゃぐフロアの上 頭中さゆさゆぶる
Playing on the floor, shaking your brain!
Hey DJ シシャフトせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ, keep it simple, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
波に乗って弾け跳ねろ ファンキーナイ
Ride the wave, bursting, jumping, funky night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー 朝まで ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, miracle number all night long!
ミラーボール スモークのにおい
Mirrorball, the smell of smoke,
溶けるようなハーモニー
a harmony that'll make you melt.
身にまとって踊り明かす
Wrap it around you and dance the night away,
がむしゃらなまま得
recklessly getting into it!
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ play it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number!
Hey DJ シシャフトせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ, keep it simple, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
波に乗って弾け跳ねろ ファンキーナイ
Ride the wave, bursting, jumping, funky night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー 朝まで ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, miracle number all night long!
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey, DJ play it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
Feeling higher and higher!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライ×3 みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number!
はい！というわけで気分上々でしたー！
Yes! So that was "Kibun Joujou↑↑"!
そして新衣装な！やっかよんきも新衣装が来た！
And my new outfit! Yay, the new outfit is here!
やったー！やってやったぜ！はい！
Yay! We did it! Yes!
あのね、昨日の配信でも
You know, even in yesterday's stream,
色々とよそがあって すごい似てる人が多くてびっくりしちゃいましたね。
there were various outfits and a lot of people who looked very similar, so I was quite surprised.
やっぱこういう衣装がみんなよかったのかなってっていう感じで。
I felt like maybe everyone liked this kind of outfit.
はい！早速ね、ちょっとずつ見せていこうかなって思います。
Yes! So I'd like to show you little by little right away!
まず、靴からですね。
First, the boots!
見てブーツ。ブーツ、ブーツに私のモチーフの星が入ってます。
Look at these boots. The boots have my star motif on them.
そしてね、レースですね。こちらレースの靴下。
And also lace! These are lace socks.
めっちゃ可愛い！ありがとう！
So cute! Thank you!
そして、ちょっとね足が
And, well, my legs...
いっぱい見えての恥ずかしいんですけど、からのはこちらパンツスタイル！
it's a bit embarrassing to show them off so much, but next is this pants style!
からの、ほら、ロゴのね、この色っていうのがかかととかに使われております。ね？
And see, the color of the logo is used on the heels and stuff, you know?
そして、実はね、この胸元のパーカーなんですけど、胸元のところには「あんきも」と「ぬんぬん」のなんか何これお団子みたいのに「ぬんぬん」って書いてあります。
And actually, this hoodie at the chest has "Ankimo" and "Nun Nun" written like dango dumplings that say "Nun Nun".
からのネックレスとチョーカーを付けました。
And I added a necklace and a choker!
そして、上は帽子ですね。こっちに私のモチーフ...
And on top, a hat! On this side, my motif...
フードが入って、ねっ、
The hood is on, see?
ここにはあんきもも、ぬんぬんがいます。
Ankimo and Nun-nun are right here.
そして、後ろですね。
And here's the back.
後ろのセーターはこんな感じです。
The sweater in the back looks like this.
全体で見るとこんな感じですね。
Overall, it looks something like this.
ちょっと横から見るとわかるかな?
Can you tell if you look from the side?
ここから、フードをね、付けてるんですけど、あー、フードの形、これなんだろうね?
I have a hood on... I wonder what shape this hood is?
ねー。
Right?
このフードがどんな感じになっているかは、
You can see what this hood looks like
明日の振り返り配信でお披露目したいと思っているので、ぜひぜひ明日も見に来てくれると嬉しいです、
in tomorrow's recap stream, so I'd be super happy if you came!
よろしくねっ。よろしくねー。
See you tomorrow!
どっちのあんきもさっき歌ってたんだろ?
Which Ankimo was singing earlier?
あんきも増えましたね。
Ankimo increased!
ステージも見てくださいよ、ちょっとね、変わったの気づきますか?
Did you notice the stage changed?
あんきもの形がね、DJきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅきゅって、やってる
Ankimo's shape is like a DJ...
ヘッドホンつけたりとかしておりますね、ぬんぬんも盛り上がっとるよ。
Nun-nun is wearing headphones and getting hyped too!
ってことで、ここからはちょっと盛り上がる曲を歌っていきたいなと思っています。
So from here, I want to sing a more exciting song!
次の曲いってみよう!
Let's go to the next song!
サラマンダー ホットが良くない?
Isn't the salamander hot?
やっぱ大問題?
It's a big problem after all?
ねえ “だって” は良くない?
Hey, isn't "but" not good?
“もっと” が聴きたい
I want to hear "more"
頭の中は最高更新中
My head is constantly updating with the best!
サラマンダー
Salamander
いっぱい ほしい
I want a lot of it
クセになるなんてずるいじゃない
Getting addicted to it is so unfair, right?
ねえ 知ってたんなら先に伝えといてほしいから
If you knew, I wish you had told me beforehand
ねえ もう降参です ハマっちゃって きみなしじゃだめだめになっちゃって
I surrender, I'm hooked, and I can't live without you!
リピっちゃいたい ピリっちゃいたい お代わりできるからもう1回!
I want to repeat it, pierce it, can I have seconds? One more time!
サラマンダー ホットが良くない?
Isn't the salamander hot?
やっぱ大問題?
It's a big problem after all?
ねえ “だって” は良くない?
Hey, isn't "but" not good?
“もっと” が聴きたい
I want to hear "more"
頭の中は最高更新中
My head is constantly updating with the best!
やめられないのよ やめたくないのよ ちゃんとふーして火傷したくないなら
I can't stop, I don't want to stop, if you don't want to get burned!
いっぱい ほしい 溺るとかばっちり止まらない
I want a lot, and my drool won't stop at all!
サラマンダー
Salamander
何回でも メラメラになって仕上がりたい
No matter how many times, I want to burn bright red!
ねえ 生き急いじゃってあっちっち 猫舌だからめんどくさい
Rushing through life makes it too hot, I'm a scaredy-cat so it's a pain
リピっちゃいたい ピリっちゃいたい お代わりできるからもう1回!
I want to repeat it, pierce it, can I have seconds? One more time!
サラマンダー ホットが良くない?
Isn't the salamander hot?
やっぱ大問題?
It's a big problem after all?
ねえ “だって” は良くない?
Hey, isn't "but" not good?
“もっと” が聴きたい
I want to hear "more"
頭の中は最高更新中
My head is constantly updating with the best!
サラマンダー とくにだめじゃん やっぱ絶好調?
Salamander, especially bad, are you in great shape?
ねえ 正直じゃない? 本音が聴きたい
Hey, aren't you honest? I want to hear the truth!
頭の中は最高更新中
My head is constantly updating with the best!
やめられないのよ やめたくないのよ ちゃんとふーして火傷したくないなら
I can't stop, I don't want to stop, if you don't want to get burned!
抜け出したいけど抜け出せないのよ ちゃんとふーして火傷したくないなら
I want to break free but I can't, if you don't want to get burned!
サラマンダー 抜け出したいけど抜け出せないのよ
Salamander, I want to break free but I can't!
ちゃんとふーして火傷したくないなら
If you don't want to get burned, do it properly!
サラマンダー
Salamander
ちゃんとふーして火傷したくないなら
If you don't want to get burned, do it properly!
みんな 声を合わせて! はいっ!
Everyone, sing together! Ready, go!
電子の海は今日も晴れ時々雪
The electronic sea is clear with occasional snow today!
前略、電子の海は今日も
Greetings, the digital sea is today as well,
晴れ、時々雪、ところによりパフェ
sunny, sometimes snow, with parfaits in places.
前人未踏のテラバイ島で
On Terabyte Island, where no one has stepped before,
またどこかのあなたを＝待機中＝
I'm waiting for you somewhere— = Standby =
偶然だって必然の合図
Even coincidence is a sign of destiny,
受信送信は見えない糸でしょ
connected by invisible threads of transmission and reception.
断然こっちがしっくりくる
This way definitely feels right at home.
enter×Space で Escape
Escape with Enter × Space!
The Boooom!ここは0と1の楽園
The Boooom! This is a paradise of zeros and ones.
The Boooom!広く深い世界から見出しそして
The Boooom! Discovering it from a vast and deep world and then—
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin', Surfin'!
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here,
良いも狂いもいただきます
and have your fill of thrills and madness!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
手と手と取ってで
Hand in hand,
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
let's dance the night away in a daydream!
攻略！電子の海は今日も
Conquest! The digital sea is today as well,
赤、緑でとにかくいっぱい一杯
red and green, overflowing with everything!
悠々自適のテラバイ島で
On Terabyte Island of carefree ease,
お待ちかねのいつもの ＝開始中＝ (えい！)
the long-awaited usual = In Session = (Hey!)
そんな こんな どんな もんな あんな ような こと くだらなさこそが至福の時でしょ
Such things, like this, whatever they are—silliness itself must be pure bliss, right?
のんびりで ぐーたらで あーだ こーだ で いこう
Let's take it easy, be lazy, and go with all our debates.
command×Delete で Respawn
Respawn with Command × Delete!
The Boooom!ここは雲の向こうの未来
The Boooom! This is the future beyond the clouds.
The Boooom!狭く暗いブラウザじゃ物足りないの
The Boooom! A narrow, dark browser just isn't enough!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin', Surfin'!
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here,
酸いも甘いも忘れてさ
forgetting both the bitter and sweet!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
手と手と取ってで
Hand in hand,
白昼夢中 夢中にするわ 覚えてて
I'll make you spellbound in a daydream, remember that!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin', Surfin'!
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here,
辛いも暗いも忘れてさ
forgetting both pain and sorrow!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
手と手と取ってで
Hand in hand,
白昼夢中にするわ 覚えてて
making you daydream, remember that!
サーフィン みんなサーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', everyone, Surfin'!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin', Surfin'!
こちらを見て見て
Look and see over here,
空に輝く奇跡を
to the miracle shining in the sky!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
手と手と取ってで
Hand in hand,
ぱっと夢中夢中で飛べ！飛べ！飛べ！
jump, jump, jump in a sudden daydream!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
こちらに来て来て
Come on over here,
酸いも甘いも頂きます
and accept both the bitter and sweet!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin', Surfin'!
手と手と取ってで
Hand in hand,
白昼夢中 夢中で踊り明かしましょう
let's dance the night away in a daydream!
ふー！というわけで、生誕祭ライブ2023新衣装お披露目…
Woo! And with that, the Birthday Live 2023 new outfit reveal...
というわけで、サナマンダとエレクトリカルサーフィンでしたー！
That was "Sanamanda" and "Electrical Surfin'"!
のりのりな曲を最後に持ってきました！まあ最後って言ってもまだあるんですけどね。
We brought this upbeat song to the very end! Well, saying the end, there's still more to come though.
さあそんな感じで、ここで…
Now, with that said, right here...
なんと！グッズのごちが…グッズのお口が、あると…えい！
What's this! There's goods... goods announcements, right here... Tada!
というわけで、グッズ告知を見ていきましょう！どん！
And with that, let's take a look at the merchandise lineup! Tada!
ときのそら 誕生日記念2023 5月26日販売開始
Tokino Sora Birthday Commemoration 2023 - On sale May 26th
誕生日記念フルセット 記念ボイス1種 記念グッズ3種 ポップアップアクリルスタンド あん肝ぬいぐるみ そらとおそろいキャップ
Birthday Commemorative Full Set: 1 Voice, 3 Goods (Pop-up Acrylic Stand, An肝 Plushie, Sora Matching Cap)
そして誕生日記念フルセット 購入特典は直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードです！
And the purchase bonus for the Full Set is a cheki-style bromide card with a handwritten signature!
いえーい！かわいい！ほんとにかわいいね！はーい、というわけで詳しく見ていきましょうか！
Yay! So cute! Truly adorable! Let's take a closer look at each one!
はい！というわけでまず1つ目はこちら、ポップアップアクリルスタンド！こちらはもちろんイラストおるだん先生に描いていただきました！
Yes! First up is the Pop-up Acrylic Stand! This was illustrated by Orudan-sensei, of course!
そして、続いてはこちら！あん肝ぬいぐるみ！めっちゃ大きいんですよね！
And next is this! The An-kimo plushie! It's super huge, isn't it?
そして続いてはこちら、そらとおそろいキャップ！
And next is the Sora matching cap!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
よろしくお願いします！
I'm looking forward to it!
キャップ可愛いよね。私もめっちゃ嬉しかったこれ
The cap is so cute, right? I was so happy too,
「キャップだ」と思って。
thinking, "It's a cap!"
ステキヤン、ありがとー！
How wonderful, thank you!
そして続いてがこちら！
And next is this!
シチュエーションボイス「誕生日はきみと一緒に遊園地」
The situational voice: "My Birthday at the Amusement Park with You."
ということで、なんかね、やっぱこういうね、元気な格好だったら遊園地行きたいでしょ。
You know, if you're dressed all energetic like this, you'd want to go to an amusement park, right?
ということでね、遊園地のシチュエーションボイスにしました！
So I made it an amusement park situational voice!
イエーイ！
Yay!
そしてこちら！
And then, this one!
ええ、誕生日記念フルセットの方には特典でチェキ風ブロマイドカードも付いてきます。
Um, the birthday celebration full set also comes with a cheki-style bromide card as a bonus.
こちらのチェキ風ブロマイドカードは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードとなっております！
This cheki-style bromide card comes with an authentic autograph!
期間限定なので、みんな買えるから今回！
It's a limited-time item, so everyone can buy it this time!
だからぜひぜひ、期間限定みんな買いに行ってもらえると、私とっても嬉しいかなって思うよ！
So please, everyone, during this limited time, I'd be super happy if you could go get it!
みんなの分たくさんサイン書きますので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll be signing lots of copies for everyone, so please look forward to it!
イエーイ！
Yay!
大丈夫、勝ち取りとかは今回は無いから！
Don't worry, there's no lottery this time!
だからみんな期間の間に行ってみてね！
So everyone, be sure to go during the period!
とりあえず最後に歌を歌って終わりにするのですが、もう最後の曲なんです。
Yes, so finally, we'll end by singing a song, and this is already the last song.
早いね。
Time flies.
さあ、よろしくお願いします。
Now then, let's get started.
まだあん肝が最終的に4人になってしまった。
Wait, Ankimo ended up being 4 people in total...
いや、後ろを回せると、いや、あの真ん中のステージを回せると、6、6、6人のあん肝がはしゃいでおるぞ！
No, if you spin the back, no, if you spin the middle stage, six Ankimos are having fun!
というわけで、え、今きたばかり、行ってくれて嬉しい。
So, um, you just got here, I'm glad you came.
でも最後の曲になります。
But it's going to be the last song.
最後の曲盛り上がっていこう！
Let's get hyped for the final song!
聞いてください、
Please listen to...
ベノム！
Venom!
足らないもの なんだ？ 僕らの人生
What is it that's missing from our lives?
正解どこなんだ 探せよ探せ
Where is the right answer? Look for it, look for it!
例外ない 二進も三進も
There are no exceptions, no matter what we try.
零下いらん なら劣化いらんね
If it's below zero, we don't need deterioration either.
正味クソゲーだ カラカラ回れ
Frankly, it's a crap game, spinning round and round.
倦怠モード「苦」だ 僕らの人生
In burnout mode, "suffering" is our life.
校内猛毒だ 屈めよ屈め
It's toxic inside the school, so bow down.
盛大 knight 和気あいあいゴッコは
A grand knight party, playing friendly games
成敗 die by 生産性ない
Ends in defeat, die by zero productivity.
後悔もう「猛毒だ」 笑えよ笑え
Regrets are already a "deadly poison," so smile.
心のレシピは
The recipe for the heart is
かまちょ味 寂ジャンキー
Attention-seeking flavor, loneliness junkie.
だんだん強がって
Pretending to be strong more and more,
ドロドロに塞ぐ
Getting clogged up in the sludge.
毒々飲み込んで 苦しんで泣いて
Swallowing down the poison, suffering and crying,
逃げ出せないのさ ベノベノム
You can't run away from it, veno-venom.
さよなら
Goodbye.
あらま 急いで 孤独 毒 流るるる
Oh my, in a hurry, loneliness and poison flowing on.
(愛をもっと) ちょうだいな
(Give me more love) Give it to me.
ねぇ 痛い 痛いのはい とんでけ
Hey, it hurts, make the pain go away.
存在感 地毒毒 こぼるるる
Presence, earthly poison spilling over and over.
(ないの？ もっと)
(Isn't there more?)
愛(愛) 愛！(愛！) 叫べ ベノム、目！
Love, love! Shout it out, venom, eyes!
最高点ゼロだ 僕らの人生
The highest score is zero in our lives.
断zenテンションlowだ 屈めよ屈め
Absolutely low tension, bow down.
論理night てっぺん回って
Logic night, past midnight,
朗報ない脳内hopeもう一回
No good news in my brain's hope, once again.
オーバードーズ系だ 上がれよ上がれ
It's an overdose type, get high, get high.
心のなかみは
What's inside the heart is
無理オブ無理ジャンキー
Impossible-of-impossible junkie.
どんどん強がって
Pretending to be strong more and more,
バラバラに塞ぐ
Shattering into pieces.
毒々飲み込んで 苦しんで泣いて
Swallowing down the poison, suffering and crying,
逃げ出せないのさ ベノベノム
You can't run away from it, veno-venom.
さよなら
Goodbye.
あらま 急いで 孤独 毒 流るるる
Oh my, in a hurry, loneliness and poison flowing on.
(愛をもっと) ちょうだいな
(Give me more love) Give it to me.
ねぇ 痛い 痛いのはい とんでけ
Hey, it hurts, make the pain go away.
存在感 既読欲 欲しがるる
Presence, desire for "message read," craving more.
(ないの？ もっと)
(Isn't there more?)
愛(愛) 愛！(愛！) 滅べ ベノム、目！
Love, love! Perish, venom, eyes!
放課後ドキドキ回るるる
After school, heart pounding, spinning around.
障害な ネー、痛い痛いのおしえて
No obstacles, hey, teach me what hurts.
存在価値ドクドクこぼるるる
Value of existence, throbbing and spilling over.
消えるるる
Disappearing...
(ハイ ハイ ハイ ハイ ハイ)
(Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!)
吸い愛成功 録々流るるる
Success in sucking love, recording and flowing on.
頂戴な ネー、痛い痛いのおしえて
Give it to me, hey, teach me what hurts.
存在価値ドクドクこぼるるる
Value of existence, throbbing and spilling over.
欲しがるる
Craving more.
(ハイ ハイ)
(Yeah, yeah)
叫べベノム 叫べベノム 叫べベノム ね！
Shout venom, shout venom, shout venom, hey!
今日は本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
本当に……
Thank you so much...